PERSONAL RESUME



Michael Zhao

Basic info

- Region: Guangzhou
- D.O.B.: 1988.8.7
- Political status: None

Contact

- 13660113008
- flybirdgroup16@gmail.com

Self-assessment

Work ability: Accumulated profound work experience in project management. Familiar with overall management of the project with the control of essential processes and the smooth implementation.

Comprehensive ability: Excellent at communication and team management with logical thinking and execution. Able to work under pressure and love to accept challenges.

EDUCATION

Sun Yat-Sen University

-- Master of Business Administration 2019-2022

University of North Carolina at Pembroke

Pembroke, NC, United States

-- Bachelor of Science (Exchange Program)

2008-2010

Guangdong University of Finance and Economics

Guangzhou, China

Guangzhou, China

-- Bachelor of Science

2007-2011

EXPERIENCE

HSBC Technology Development Engineer

2022-Now

- Based in HSBC Bank and work development Engineer for Cloud Devops development.
- Adopt the Agile processes/principles/methods (daily tools: JIRA, confluence) and to lead development team to complete the delivery of each project
- Designed and developed general ETL programs with the establishment of cloud infrastructure, allocation of ETL jobs, and tracking of the testing process.
- Take part in as front-end and back-end engineer an Innovation Project (Connect Us) which has gained Internal Angel Fund support. This project is building connect between colleagues based on their hobbies, departments, location, skills and share event activities to colleagues

Gientech Technology (Pactera)

Senior Engineer

2020-2022

- Based in HSBC Bank and work as Tech Lead /Team lead to manage, guide and support colleagues. Responsible for the Agile project management of Financial IT Projects.
- Adopt the Agile processes/principles/methods (daily tools: JIRA, confluence) and to lead development team to complete the delivery of each project
- ➤ Designed and developed general ETL programs with the establishment of cloud infrastructure, allocation of ETL jobs, and tracking of the testing process.
- Under English working environment, conduct daily communications with project stakeholders in Australia, Europe, India, Hong Kong and other countries/regions, to remove obstacles of the project

Self-employment

Freelancer Entrepreneur

2012 - 2014

Analyzed and selected products from suppliers, identified niche market, conducted market research, did competitors' analysis and sold products to different markets.

Project

Project: Connect-us Innovation

Duties:

- ➤ Building Graph relationship network using Python. Ingest Data in Neo4j
- > Development Front-end based on Backend data to convert into web pages.
- > Graph Visulaization development by React

Project: Cloud Data Solutions

Duties:

- Prepare the Data migration plan, and design the technical solutions of data migration.
- Lead the team to develop SQL/scripts with proper work assignment. Migrate data from on Perm to BigQuery on Google Cloud via Juniper.
- Organized materials for customers and optimized user training materials, user operations manuals, and go-alive FAQ, etc.
- Responsible for the business cooperation work with project stakeholders globally, for related Data Migration solutions
- Inspection, measurement and testing to verify the outputs to meet stakeholders' acceptance criteria. Coordinated with various parties with the notify of assistance work before go-alive. Notified the schedule of the plan prior to assist in the go-alive work.

Project: Report Generation Automation

Duties:

- Organized the report with proper work assignment based on requirements.
- ➤ Dealt with high volume data issues of the report via GCP native component Dataproc(Spark). Utilized scalable native cloud platform component for reliable elastic processing.
- ➤ Lead Team to build up a server in Google Cloud and setup connection to outbound data to Perpetual's server via SFTP.
- Prepared reports based on the data structure with the integrated upstream data sources and prepared production reports based on the data structure with specific parameters.

Certifications or Skills

- Language skills: Trilingual in English (business level), Mandarin(native) and Cantonese(native)
- > Office skills: Proficient in Microsoft Office; Confluence; JIRA
- IT Skills:
 - Coding: Skilled in Python, Spark, Linux, Flask, Terraform, SQL.
 - Devops: Kubernetes, Jenkins, Docker, GCP Cloud
 - Analysis: Understand the common concept of Machine Learning, like Supervised learning & Unsupervised learning.
 - Version Control: GitHub Management
- > IT certification:
 - ➤ Google Cloud Certified-Professional Data Engineer
 - ACP (Alibaba Cloud Computing Engineer),
 - > ACA (Big Data Assistant Engineer)
 - > HCIA (Huawei Artificial Intelligence Engineer)